Hello, my name's eric flow.
I am a software engineer on the surface hub team.
And, I have...for microsoft for over twenty five years on operating systems
in my opinion this is the coolest project I've ever
worked on this is the surface hub this presentation today is going to be
all about writing applications to run on the surface
up little housekeeping first ...appreciate your
...so I'll show the slide again at the very end but if you could scan
...r code...send us feedback we would really appreciate it.
So,...talk about today
...give you a brief overview of the surface hub and then invite roberto to
come up and show you how to build some apps for it and then he's
got a ticket to the next level is going to show you how to tailor your app so it's
optimized to run on the surface hub we should have
time for qa at the end so you guys could hold your questions the end we really appreciate it.
bill gates bounded microsoft he had a vision?
His vision was a pc on every desk
and every home writing microsoft software that vision
empowered individuals...very little for groups.
The surface hub is here to fill that space the surface hub
is all about empowering groups it will be as...to the
space as the pc was to the individual and to the desk.
As I mentioned the...subs all
about empowering groups it can be used in a lot of different places,
for example, you could put in a conference room you can put in a boardroom you could put
in a small meeting space.
The goal of this device is to bring together people that
are both local and remote so they can collaborate so
they can brainstorm so they can run apps that you guys are going to write.
So, they can be more productive.
The surface hub is an integrated computing
device that has everything that you need for standard copper
shown built into it across the top of it...a...it's
gotten dual...p cameras in it it's got sensors for
light and promotion it has wi-fi support bluetooth
...has dual pans
and dual charging stations on it built-in speakers.
It also has support for nfc.
The screen lcd with anti-nuclear cody knowledge is supports
...input
and touch inputthis particular one here look at here is the eighty four-inch model runs
...the four-k resolution on it we also have a fifty five-inch version runs
attend adp both of them are on display over the quarter
...the solution showcase this.
Integrated device has everything that you need for typical conference room all
you need to dude is role in their and supply one...our to it has everything else...need.
So, because it's such a large-screen and its communal
...collaborative actually can be used in unique ways this is not your typical
pc they just go...log onto it can be used.
In some of the pictures you see here, for example,...lower right it could be used in a media scenario it
could be used in a conference room absolutely it could be used on a factory
floor so there's unique opportunities for you guys to write apps that
leveraged this device so.
Imagine that you're writing and app that presents
like pages of information a story.
Or their reports okay.
Because you have so much real-estate to work with when you present this information to
the users you can do it in a way that makes sense for them to collaborate you could have all the pages
stacked up and then the user could flip through them or they could take the
pages...could...them out across the large-screen or they may zoom in
...the zoom out right it gives them the ability to customize the information to the way that
makes sense for them to work together so another area
is remote collaboration this device is wonderful for
remote collaboration, you know, why because I personally
work remotely three days a week with my team and microsoft and I actually
call-in and I have...on this device is amazes the audio is great the
video is great also if you go to the solution
showcase over here on the second-floor...to of the set-up there's a couple of
isv are showing their remote collaboration
applications over there they're great examples please you get some time go see them okay?
The surface have though is also more than bringing people together it can bring people and
...devices together multiple devices can hook up to
it allows for better information sharing.
Let's talk about market size for little bit worldwide.
Fifty million meeting spaces.
Of which about twenty million of them are the typical large conference
room but the fastest-growing segment is the sm space some people call...space
some component open space thirty million and growing corporations are spending
a lot of money on these meeting spaces so for a conference room
some are spending up to fifty thousand dollars to buy all the peripherals that
they need to outfit this conference room to work for their situation and for
the small ones are...up to ten thousand-dollars to buy profiles...so guys
here's an opportunity here for you guys to make money okay.
Now I would like to do a brief demo of the surface
hub and I'm going to ask murrow to come up here in hell.
We're going to pretend to be a software developer house okay...we're going to make
it out and we're going to they can
...you can review cheers you can flip through pictures of chairs and you can reviewand,
give your opinions autumn now we're not having a scheduled meeting we're going to have
and ad-hoc meeting okay so when you saw the welcome screen
...screen that was just up here it offers three big
buttons audit these are the primary tasks right...the most common things we
have a meeting it's like you want-to call somebody or you want to use the white board or you want
...connect to it with your phone or your laptop it also it offered a
short-cut
the start menu so that you guys when you write apps they can get your apps easily
...this particular example okay you saw that when I lifted the
...devices smart enough to know a...I want to
...words that automatically started the white board so now we're
...I were going to draw out a couple of pages of our app
ok so if I take the first page would you be willing to draw the second page of
our sure so let's go on a drawn black on
Yeah, this is a non
...tm software so let's try it again ...close one node here.
And, once again we're very excited to be able to bring this
trait from like where it's made and bring here to you guys okay, there
...so here I have my notes and we're drawing here are pages
...our app have some menus and well that's a pretty
chair sorural ...you and I being
...we're probably not the best designers right and my little stick man probably not
...here but the surface hub gives us the ability to bring
...content from other things one of the things that we could do is we could loop in
james he's a great designer ok so if we want to loop...we could push the
...for business button we could punch and...this number and he would show up here is a
remote tandy and then we could share this with him...us feedback right but there's
other ways that we can get feedback here so another example maybe
...a phone right and he happened to have some great pictures a chairs audit, yeah,
he could wirelessly project and then he could put pictures
up here we could then capture...from his device and
paste them right here into one node and the size of course third-party apps like the ones you can build so
this is the start menu and you can bring content from other apps into your collaboration
...meeting or even just use the app by itself that's right so we have many ways
to gather information into this one note share we can annotate
on it the best part is...I bet you I bet you a whole bunch
of you have done this okay how many of you have gone to the white board and you drawn all over
...get your cell...you take a picture of it right and then
...yourself all right so it worked okay but you'd never go back and
...picture again digit this solves the problem okay right down
here little email icon you can
save this entire canvas into a one
node file and then have it email to everybody that you're working with so then you can continue
on with your project after you have left this...you can drop it on your own one node
...nodes together with your...nodes so on so
then let's pretend that we're all done okay what we would normally do is say I'm all done we'll
walk away so you would push the armed and...here now since we're
...to use...I'm not actually going to end okay but if I were to push the yes button it
will reset the device it will return back to the big blue welcome screen you saw
is ready for the next meeting okay, yeah, so, at this point?
I'm going to ask for...take-over and he's going to talk about building some applications
...for userthank you so much so let's move over to the
...little bit and I'll talk a little bit about developing for the surface
...and many present myself I'm roberta I'm also sausage in the service...team and
is really exciting to be here and show this beautiful device it's really are
we're very proud to be able to display and have you played at the showcase
...so let's talk about developing for surface hub and here you can see this beautiful three-d
mapped app so this is like just to give you a little bit of a glimpse of what can you do
...such a big-screen and,
we notice that people on the showcase love finding their home...the three-d mapping oy but it's something called
to do ...just a beautiful screen and you have to think differently when...develop
apps rate but actually developing apps it's not hard at all it's very easy so
let's talk a little bit about that?
Building apps for surface hub
service hub is a member of the windows
...device family we have devices all the way from the smallest
internet things device imbedded device although way to
our giant screens passing through xbox...all of those run universal
windows apps and you heard about them about a thousand times is conference and I'll say a few more
service have runs the universal windows apps and that's the main thing you have to remember you
maker app run on all devices if you think about screen sizes you will
scale-up to the surface hub but also you can tweak...you can make a little bit better you can use some
of the unique capabilities of this device to improve your app even more even though it's to a
universal windows app so let's talk a little bit about the device families so, you know,
that windows categorize their devices into family so you have, for example,
the mobile family includes the sm tablets in the phones and have the best
of family xbox follow...so on
and the surface hub it's running windows stand but it's part of the windows
...family were called the windows team family why you need to know that you need to
know that if you want to code our make some customization of your app
...specific for the surface hub because if you just use screen size you wouldn't be able to differentiate
between any four-k desktop and the surface of the resolutions the same
you india which are...for the fifty-five...she wouldn't be able to differentiate between
...phone and...surface...because they're both nntp
resolutions not enough to know where your running resolution scaling it's not enough?
you need to know your part of the windows team...family I'll show you how to customize for that device family
in a...so I talk about apps building apps it's easy
...it will take all your skills from universal at develop because surface
...runs the universal apps they scale automatically if you
think about large-screen this is a large-screen you will work if you think about four-k or tended
to be if you think about how your control should be place you
...very well also if you don't have a service qubit you want to see
...would look like to design and app specially example visual
studio twenty fifteen has a preview on this...designer that is the surface hub eighty
four-inch so together with phones and tablets you can switch...designer to show...service have
...four-inchalso remember the resolution that's the key to remember farce screen
...this one is four-k running
...hundred-fifty percent and fifty five-inch is
...running at a hundred-percent scaling so...fifty percent
...scaling nab four-k not that complicated to remember and also all this information
...on the documentation to.
Of course you can create a neutral x eighty-six
...sixty-four package we don't spar arm because all...processors are executed
for and star submission you have to think about two things remember to a key points when you
submit...start first...make sure windows team
are windows universal are included in your platforms because you can submit apps that
go only to phone are only to desktop if you want habit on the surface...
its windows team and second one is the seat licensees...because this
device is going to be for enterprises we expect that it pros and admins
we'll go and buy apps in the business store or just download apps
...the business store and then...the company so-if you want to be part of that you want
...plight to the business store you need to opting to
...so that the admins can do that so that's great.
Let's move on now to design and let's get our hands libm are dirty with the
designing...thinking about an effort...surface hub what do you have to think about as
your developing your app so first thing you have to think about when you are
tailoring once again you're app just runs but you can do things to improve there's a lot of design tips
I'm going to give herefirst one is that the session
conserve office session so like here we were in the welcome screen and then we
enter the session and then we did stuff and then we finish the session and everything was
gone this is what's going to happen every time...user enters a conference room and tries to do something
with the surface up so they will do that they'll be productive
...get stuff done and as they are finishing we're going to erase all
their contents why do we do that because the next people are going to come into the conference room and we don't want
them to see that content so it's very much about trusts
it's we want people to go to conference rooms and get out and trust their data safe
so in each of as a developer make sure to not save anything on the device because
...will be erased optimized for
...touch...key.
When you're talking about otherwise this big it's so visual is
so tactile you really want to be on the screen you don't want to be a
mouse or keyboard for sure and, you want to make sure that you use all the capabilities that are
sensors give you can use multiple touches in-band at the same time which is something very unique and you
can also differentiate between...touch you can make sure that dutch will
...the content while...will...on the content so you want
to make sure to use those true to your advantage of course the size of the
...important if you are making a presentation...you want to make sure things are full-screen and
use all the resolution because we want everyone in the room to see...the same time if you're close to
the screen if things are too big I can't even see the whole screen when I'm
like just to give an example and I'm right here I can't even see the whole screen only see like an
...in the middle so you can use that also sure advantage you can put the important things in the
center and put the secondary controls on the sides so interesting things that
you can think about when you...size...I'm going to go into each of response pointing more...
So, I thought about cleanup.
Why am I talking so much about cleaner because this is very unique to the surface hub not many
devices have this concept of cleaning up and resetting everything when you're done with your
at the service have does because it's a communal device
...will be just hanging out there in the hubble space and conference room
people go use it and get out that's how it's going to operate during the day and because of that at the end of
every session we want to be sure to not leave anything so we're going to
erase all application data documents pictures media temporary files
that settings everything and the key for-you developers app settings
app data gone so you don't want to save anything locally you want to make sure that all
your data is saved either on the cloud or on a personal device like a phone
...tablet that is...should...remember we have so many
sensors you can actually use that your advantage you can use nfc and
...the phone should download your content or you can use the phone to login you can this
some equal things so that the user can start fresh and make sure that the data
that goes with them instead of being the lead so far for the most
common one which is the white where we had a solution...sending the notes by email but you could imagine,
for example, pairing with the phone and doing a lot of cool things like that are unique to this
big form factor it's a divisor invites you to come and...and connect?
Also think about first-run experiences you're probably
everyone has seen apps that when you get in the app it says welcome
to the app let's take a tour let's do a tutorial endpoint
aerosmith thing saying this is how you do things so this is
...very useful for mobile apps but,
it's in the surface how because you're...doesn't know if it's the first run
...second-round instagram because they don't have local data you need to be aware that first-run experience
two-run every time so you'll have that and considered reducing
...first-run experience or even removing completely because on the first-time you be great
on the third-time...be really annoying and after the fifth time they mites really avoid
your app so you don't want to be putting those little tutorials every single time?
So, let's talk about the design and
scale and how close you are to the device so...are user research
wi-fi very useful to divide the interaction to choose
...of engagement so we calls on one is own
to zone one is when you're close to the device it's about up to one arm's length of the
device person that...on one is really touching the device
...out writing on the devices really close to the device sometimes they are not sometimes they're
just like discussing with someone else but they're that close and that's the only have to be aware
that they don't see the whole screen they probably have a limited a
awareness a cone of awareness in front of them that's the area they can see and
...when you are further away from the device then they could be watching presentation they could
be just hanging around the device and talking about some content they could be
...could have other devices in their hands might maybe...phone maybe a tablet you want to make sure you
...that they might be...in a conference room so you want you
...make sure that when you're tailing for zone...you and
make sure that everything is big and readable invisible so, for example, this map is great on zone
too because you guys can see the map is very visual but at the same time I have a little bit of zone one
controls here the smaller menus which are for me the presenter so you can
...mix and match them as your scenario both so with...zones in...are also let me
tell you about the size of...of course so...goes more or less up to for meters
...device and up to six meters with an eighty
four-inch device off-course bigger devices give you a bigger zone through a bigger engagements?
Even though here in this conference room I believe people although in the back which would be outside...onto
...to see...part of this presentation so you can adapt that your scenario but nobody does
...shoe is on one's own...this concepts off engagement zones there's a lot of
things you can do to improve your apps to twitter apps let's talk about positioning
...about the users context in basra if they're sitting down if there standing up and they have
another device if what where are the user in the relationship with the
space and the device make controls reachable and that might sound ...
sound redundant but you need to make sure people can actually thatcher your controls here the control
there on the top are hard to reach unless you are
...eric they're hard to reachif the on the talk so you should be aware that some people have access
to be requirements they might have a wheelchair or might have difficulties moving their arms
...make sure that the main controls should be on the bottom and you
should think about which controls you put in the center and on the sites I
give the example here off-the-shelf of the surface of...so here we have the
...buttons on the right side and on the left...why do we do that on both sides because
there secondary control they're not like here in the middle
but also I don't want people to go and walk all the way across to start...I want them to be able to
...from either side I don't want them to also as a presenter...to
...the content should start immediately so you think about that like think about
occlusion think about how do...the size of the device because we have all
the space we can afford to have a controls always there?
I also think abouts the brightness and proximity to the screen so when you make your
...very bright like white's...be uncomfortable after a while for the user
...be close to the screen...own one at the same timezone to
...image might pop out better and they might be able to redid better so consider how you're going to apply
...an change that...in relationship to the to the proximity.
of course scale contents and controls appropriately so if you this is this
control is about the size of my failure and that's great but if I took a phone app imagine
...took a phone app where the controls the size of my finger and
just proportionally scaled up and then the control now is about the size of my hand so
you've gotta be careful when you do scaling be smart about... about where the controls are in
the screen sometimes a control...here it's here on the bottom it's not exactly comfortable to be
hitting all the time so this controls they don't have them all the time it's fine
but you probably want to optimize to the zone that's going to be most convertible.
So, now let's go and move on to actual decode part which is my favorite part
...english is not my first language as you can notice but actually code is my
first language I imagine you all speex code with me let's go...speak a little bit of
zeppelin csharp so why do they choose demo in csharp I believe most of you
are familiar with it...is those are the technologies that we have been demoing all over and it's really
easy-to-read and understand you can use other universal universal apt
languages like cplus-plus like visual basic andfrom yesterday now we
know that java and objective see and everything is coming together is really
awesome I'm excited to be a microsoft right now let's talk a little bit about this
...so here I'm going to be the part of
a software developer on a design firm so my design
firm has an app that allows people...their phones to review
design that were saying each of them so the clients can receive the...and say I like or I don't like the
app...like the design so let's take a look at that
...to move onto my display.
...seizure your favorite friend.
So, here we just show you this app that we have running onphone form
...small tab with form factor so here this is a universal app that we
develop before and this app is for clients
to go and say if they like or if they don't like their designs
on the goal the client can go in quickly swipe and say well, you know,
I really like this so far I like this.
And, you can say I like this and you can goes...
I dome once this one I do very fast very optimized for that on-the-go if you
recognise furniture we actually took the pictures here in the conference so.
It's a it's a...that's very interesting
in conference furniture they're, they're probably trying to make a conferences cools do so,
here I'm going to open the menu and it's navin global navigation menu so it's an app
it's working very well it's...for mobile it uses the patterns that mobile
...expect has bright blue-collar it pops out well on the phone I can
recognise quickly so it works great I can type the
common with the virtual keyboard and my clients...they take the app they walk around
...can...very quickly be...
But, now my...dot this amazing device about this giant touch-screen on
...conference rooms and nodding they ask me well why don't we tried putting that app on
the surface hub and I said that's cool because now we can invite the
clients over and they can discuss with us
they can discuss on the conference room instead of doing that just on the goal and I
said sure let's try that out so I'm going to just run this app on the surfaceand,
let's see what it looks like so I'm going to change here to...machine we're using the regular
...no magic here you guys know it very well let's see
if the remote is up the checkbook.
I think it is I think it is I got to deployments.
Although the remote operations taking longer so the wrote the bagger has some flaking as with
the network let's just open it again okay there it is...retry.
So, yeah, I'm just going to apply to the remote...the...let's try that again.
They this so...same app
...windows app so no magic here we can apply the app
any will show up on every device but you can see that like I really tailored
...phones and small screens I didn't make a layout for large-screen
so this is a little bit of...example if I had like a desktop layout you would definitely look
better...looks so, much like the phone stretched up you could actually go and think about the screen
size but here I just had my phone and I my phone app and I want to run that universe
...any runs I can do all the same passe can swipe up I
...come here and typed we using the virtual
keyboard because see the virtual keyboard is a little bit less convertible to type on this vertical surface so
you have to we have to improve that also can see that the app
it works ok but the pictures a little bit large because remember my...of
awareness is about here so I can see this but I can't really see the
whole picture when I'm at zone one interacting with the device so I need to make the picture
be a little smaller more censored also the background is headed pops very much on the phone
...cool I like the...blue-collar but here I one is something
...muted because it's...bright it...that from the main content and
...the menu the many works and I can I can
through open it up but this menu is not using the real-estate that
I have available why do I had to click the button...every time so we could improve
there's a lot more by having the may be always open so let's go
to make those tweaks and I'm going to show you how to make those tweaks specifically for the surface
hub again I'm going to make tweaks based on the screen size there's a lot of things you can do based on the screen
size but here I'm going to make
it based on the surface hub itself which is a very unique device.
So, let's go over to visual studio back again so here you guys can see my code
...what I'm going to do here is I'm going to creates a new set of visual
states to change between surface hub
and other devices so if you don't know visual states...visual
states is how you changer layout based on some property
or some state of your app so you can create visual states for sizes for different screen
...can create visual states for I don't know if you have an error you can creative
...for the errors so there's a lot of things you can do visual states but here we're going to really
create visual stage for the surface hub so that I can make tweaks and
change properties when I'm running on that device so let me show you how I...going to do that let's open here are
main page this is just a regular demo page and here I have my split view it's the ...
of my page and I'm going to add a visual states group the same way I would
for anything else so here I have to visual
states the default and windows team so I'm going to create a visual state
...windows thing family now the first thing is how do I...the
design for that state after I have the state up what I like to do is go to blend and
...is really my favorite...for this
I really love it and I've been using it since he was called acrylic.
Expression interactive designer was...a very cool it's been a very cool
too and it's now it's like just amazing I love the features that we have here
for designing so here have on blend I'm running the designer I can see my
...five-inch phone you can see what it looks like when I'm design for the full as I said
...as well as users to have eighty
...surface hub as an option here so without having the
surface hub you can have an idea of what the layout will look like you can compare with the real one
...very similar...to the real one on the device so I'm going-to leave this one and the surface
...and I'm going to use visual states that I created to change my design for windows
...do that you click the state here so usually you're going to be
in the solution explore tab you just click the...stab?
And, then I have my to visual...windows t when you click it you can see here windows
...state recordings on and then I'm going-to go over I'm going to change some stuff
here on my app...do is I'm going to take the menu and make sure
it's always open so let's take the menu here I love this property filter
it's my it's my favorite feature on the properties designer in
...so I'm going to come here and type
in spain open through and change display mode to inline so
they'll make the menu be always open so let's see what it what it looks like to know
menu...menu great let's keep...
So, now that I have my menu here I don't need my button anymore I don't need this
button to be visible because the...is always there so
let's just collapses this button visibility collapse...gone.
Now let's talk about the main contents the main content I said the background it's a little bit...bright I'm going to
make a little bit more discrete and the way I'm going to do that is a click the main content
here animation change the background to menu background brush so I like it looks
...looks flush with the...darker more focus on the main content
and center also you can see that when I open the menu everything got little bit nudged the
...so I'm going to nudge everything back ...do that going-to-take the
...there's several ways to do it I'm going to a very quick one going to put a margin on my main
contents of minus three twenty...back...great.
Now let's talk about the picture itself the flip view so...is where I can go in flipped
...text with the comments right I'm going to go over and I said it was a
...wide like here it's nice for presentation I like
...presentation but for collaboration productivity it's not great remember this is
...ad for me to show you the designs a good...for that would be powerpoint,
for example, this is a good...for me to go and...the designs and comment on...
designs and for that I need to be able to see the whole thing when I'm actually right here in the middle of the
...so I'm going to make the image smaller so that I can I can appreciate
the whole design so, I'm going to do that by taking that picture and changing the max with
...again thousands of ways you can think about going that there are lots of talks here
...build that talk about that specifically talk about tailoring or app
for different screen sizes but I'm just going to use a simple method here I'm going to put a
macs with and I'm going to put a margin on each side so that.
So, that the flip few doesn't interfere with the menu on the left so I'm just going
...three twenty margin on each side there...now we got the pictures
...be centered and it's going to be not full-screen you guys can see over
...designer this is what I got so I'm going to save this.
And, let's just run this on the device and see what
looks like of course I'm forgetting something very important I didn't make the
states change withwhen...that advice I just created
...states but I didn't change the windows team state so how do I do that
actually I could even go and run just to show that you won't change anything just by having that
to state there so...building I'm going to talk about
...you can see it's exactly the same even though I...those streaks I didn't change
that visual state the question here is how do you change to a different visual state
when you are in a different advice and that's the key to the whole thing so, there's a concept
we introducing windows then that's...state triggers and there's one state trigger that
comes with the sdk which is really cool it's called the adaptive state trigger and with that
trigger you can take a set of visual states and change them when with our
...change on the your window so you can go and say if the with is higher
than like if there is bigger than a thousand pixels then change the state, for example, and,
that's a very common technique web developers having doing that for ages and,...great that we introduced that
...should sdk?
But, the interesting thing here is that we don't want to trigger on the with our heights are size
...trigger on the particular device family which is the windows team family once again we don't want to
confuse a four-k screen with...arcade desktop monitor we really don't want to do that we wanted to
optimize for this so how do you do that you create you can create
your own state triggers and that's what I did.
Have my own device family state trigger and just want
to show you how simple the code is really like there's two lines of actual code?
to create a state trigger you just arrived from state trigger base so here you can see I'm implementing the
...from states trigger base and state
trigger base is it only has one important method which is
sad active so the idea is when you create a trigger you-can call sat active
with true or false if you call it through that means this trigger should be activated
...the state should be activated if it's false means that triggers not active so you can
create state triggers to change between states and that's really, really easy so, this
state trigger it's pretty simple it has one property called device family any
...to active when the device family is equal to
the device family of the device I'm running now so this class analytics info
is part of windows system profile once again everything is documented you can get the version info dot
device family and you can compare that with the device family that I created when a
stance the instantiated this trigger
...how do I use it let's go to the main page and let's add a state trigger here
to my windows team states so visual states...even bigger for you guys on the
back visual state dot state triggers and then I'm going to go in here and say
...see adapted trigger comes...the adaptive trigger is the one about
size but I'm going to use my own that's the local device family state trigger and I'm going to say
the device family is windows dots team as I said
that's the thing to remember when you're talking about device family so with this trigger
I I'm sure now that when we run on the windows team device...look different and that's
I had to do it will go and apply all those changes that I made let's see if that's true.
Seeing is believing I only believe my code when it's running on the...so,
...trick that we make the main is always open the pictures in the center now I can
finally see the whole thing it's great I love those cubes that are in the theater over that and,
now I can go and say wow I like...I don't like this I can swipe through the
...always visible which means I'm using a libm are the
real-estate you can go further you could put the may on both sides you can make the menu lower you could put many
in the center you could go crazy with this I did like in just about ten minutes I did
tweaks that improve my experience quite a lot but I'm going to...last week which is
...xbox this is really my biggest gripe with anything on the surface hub that
grows from a small form factor to a large so here I have a text box and typing
here it's uncomfortable is really uncomfortable...start typing here and it works and even has the
...completion but he's really not the best...form factor for typing you can
use an external keyboard as well but you can get this so much better if you just use the
...so I'm going to make a change now is I'm going to remove that xbox and I'm going to add
...support and I'm going to keep the...in touch differentiated so they can
...the pen and swipe through the pictures with touch...show that how to do that.
Let's go back to our code once again so...to do that what you have to do is you need to change the data
template...that...view because...will be flipping through and each template has an image
...xbox me show you what it looks like now.
So, I got my flip view here...amounts you can see the whole thing so
the flip view and the data template as I said has
an image and attacks box and what I need to do is
...a new data template and I need to switch...that...the template when I
m on the windows team device so how do you do that?
So, I have created a different data template up here in my resources so
...here this is even simpler than the one that I had
...the xbox.
...a different data template that has an image within in
cameras on top and I'm going to zooming very much so you can all see in...is the word to
remember in canvas is the key to unlocking...support just by adding and in
...element you can make any control incapable with the
...support for from windows stand from direct inc all those cool
things that you'll learn about inc is just you put in canvas control...and the cool thing is that in
...by default only support spend it doesn't support the touch you can go
...change the properties to make is part painting with the dutch are
...the mouse but by the fault it only support spend which is what we want because you want
...to...and touch choose to swipe so let's see what that looks like so I'm
going to go and apply that data template which again is the same picture view
...the same data is the same of your model that a feeding this view I'm going
to go over to blends I'm going to choose once again my windows team states and
...going to go to the flip view and say when you...make
sure true changer item templates here
item template to be the inc template that I created.
And, then if I just save this and go back tvs and the...
So, it's going to build and even see that we just that change of data
template that xbox gone and now I can take my pen.
And,...I can take my pen and rights.
On the screen and also I can
continuous swiping and writing independently I can use the our of
...in touch separately I think...spent better result maybe I'm going to try the other one.
this is not any in canvas it's a step up from anything we had before you go to
direct in talk the talk all about how this is the best in
canvas microsoft has ever shipped because
...has by the fault pressure sensitive been and he has.
You can look like how the inc follows my
...very closely so he has super low latency by the
for out-of-the-box example so if you go to their
...the directing talk the talk tell-all about how this is the best
...we ever shipped out-of-the-box with one-line of them
and that's great and let's say now that I put this app on our conference rooms and people like
...people can...the bacon inc and they can use the menus they can swipe
in evaluate and say I liked picture that's great.
But, the thing is we realize that when we put this on a conference room what people really want to do is they don't want to
display by themselves they want to collaborate they want to bringing our people they
want to discuss the picture and this is a good at for one person it does the same thing
...the phone but if...bring more people how can we improve
the app even more how can we think about collaboration how can
we optimize from the ground-up for the surface hub and that's what I just did I created
a different view for this app...how to switch the views and
...do different view instead of just taking the user interface elements with visual
states create a whole new from scratch.
And, that new view is being read imagine for the conference room for the surface hub for
collaborating and I'm going to show you what that looks like right now it took me about a day to go a
day's work to go from that you to the other one of the show so that, you know,
that it's also not magic it's not crazy complicatedbecause the data is the same the code behind the
same...creating a new view so here I'm going to go back to my...cs and let me
...solution explore...have the main page is the page we were working on
and I created before another page called the surface hub page and I want to make sure that when
I...on the windows team device you should go to the service hub page so how does
that look like there's several ways of doing that once again I'm just choosing one
that's very simple which is I can use...framed...navigate on apps
...on the on launched method so here we are online ced we can navigate
through a different page according to the device type device
family sorry so here we this is the one that comes out-of-the-box with
the template I'm going to commented out and I'm going to
use the one that will do slightly different thing which
is when my device family is the windows team go to the surface
hub page otherwise go to the main page so very simple I just
change the whole page out of that and now let's take a look and see what this will look like?
So, let me run this one and ...
And, this is how we re imagine this app for the conference room and let me...a little bit of a few of the
features that I was thinking about when I was developing this one with the help of with the helping feedback of
our team backing redman so this is a screen that it's a lot more
optimized for the conference room and for the surface...form factor because
...uses the whole area of the device I put the manual on the topic is not
very important for me I maybe horizontal and is more symmetrical
the likens like buttons are bigger and I have space now to include the...but they...just to say and,
also now you can see I had this three-d carousel where
...the picture instead of the...
view because now not constrained by the space on the phone and I'm also not constrained by the battery
a memory performance of the phone so now I have a better
graphics card I can abuse the...a little bit and also I can make sure to give a
little bit of context because I have that space can give a little bit of convex to the user this is what
came this is what's coming next and I can use that just because I have this large-screen
of course I'm through optimizing for the cone of awareness I'm in the middle but I'm adding this
background and you can see the background cross fades when I
swipe actually let me put the...guys can see better?
So, you can see the background
across fades when I swipe between the pictures and then even though my awareness in the
...immersed in that design so you can make like the
designed to be immersive inclusive put the user in the context and
of course...works let me go here and eric which
...let-me know what-you think of this share?
Well, you know,
I like this chair I really like this part.
Right here ...that's an interesting part so eric
likes the chair but the thing is I don't think it goes very well with our living room, you know,
I think the
...not great so I can go here and say I don't like it and as
you notice the
application seems the transition from a one person uses two-a-two person
usage...the menu into the center and I got the buttons likens like
came I say I don't like it and now we have our own collections and now we can have a
much richer record off what happened in that discussion and I can say,
you know, tell me tell me about this one what you think this
...I really like the leather on it but the shiny steel I didn't really like that one yeah,
I think it doesn't match the table very well I don't like it either and we can keep
johan have a good record of the discussion again each one of us has
pressure sensitive band and...identification so each...has a different caller
and is associated with differ user the coolest thing you can do is imagine
what you what you're going to do when you can take this wireless...spend id
...associate with something like a credential are token and then you can
...that actually green was roberto and
blue was eric imagine that for review for collaboration for braced
army so who actually wrote this do remember that and this is super easy with the surface of the
scenario is like unleash with the surface hope?
Another over the does
...design because this...it's not magic I will point over to like some open-source
...like this cardoso is an open-source control I'll tell you how to get there it's really not
magic but the cool thing that I'm going to show in terms of code is where how do
...id how do you identify which
...is which and that's the last thing I want to demo it's going to move on to the code machine please absolutely?
There we go so that's the last thing I would like to show is how do I do the
...id and this is the surface hub page them cs and here I have the
method that does depend identification is really five lines of code super simple to do so
one cool thing about the service...is that each...has a unique wireless id and
unique wireless id will be a unique for the lifetime of your session, you know,
that each that...for all the apps that you're going to use is going to be the same so all
have to do is take the pointer point properties you can get one of those every time you click...time you
...dutch...or...this is the property you can get out of the event
arts so you can get a point-to-point and...the properties and from the point
...properties you can go in query for the wireless id usage
and the wireless id page so
those magic constance you need to know they're going to be documented and you can find that this code is on the
...you can download the slides in the website...build website and he has that piece of code?
And, of course I need to make sure that I return and notable...because if it doesn't have an
...have to return no because zero is a valid id zero could be about a or minus one
we don't know which ideas going to come out of the...so we need to return something else when it does not have an id,
... touch doesn't have an idmouse doesn't have an id but append us
...surface hub does so this is how you go in identify and then you can take that id
...with the token a credential and go crazy so.
That was it for the demo I'm going to move back to the powerpoint and finish up the...
...out of.
This...inverter I'm just going to...fargo glowed so,
let's talk about...components I just want to shot out the both work at microsoft those people sebastian
picture and...cracker and they created the carousel and we...eml
toolkit I use that only on the...demo to the cross fading the...ninety-two
...I use it should across fading so you can go and get them open-source they both work
at microsoft and those products are really coolthey have
all diversions you can get that on the slide on the website as well and finally in
summary of surface runs universal windows apps and universe
...apps are amazing their own from your hollow...
to your xbox surface...is not out of that it's exactly the same it's part of the windows
...family and that's the keyword when you want to tailored for the service
...as opposed to just any large-screen.
Up plan for session cleanup session clean-up is very important you it's going to
happen whether you want to are not and information your data is safe you need to make sure data is
start on the cloud...personal device and again use the sensors to events you can go
...a phone and download the data you can be sure that
that's going to keep the data safe optimized for
...touch-screen size once again giant screen which means lots of
opportunities to interact with it think about how you depend in touch differentiate,
differentiate between them like...for writing dutch for swiping touch for interact with the
buttons this is how people have been doing it...like and
xing times like since...writing was invented so you should...adventure that.
Think about collaboration scenarios so here I took an application that was
for an individual on the phone and I took it up for to the large-screen animated collaborative and
you can see the big difference between application for one person for two people and of course you can
think of applications for multiple people for remote people what if I
had to surface hubs one here and one in china and the
surface have been china has more people writing on this and they have different...callers and can
...see the likens like together because service hub does that across
...across remote as well so you think about the collaboration snares think about
...discussing this?
As if we were in the same room but we could be a separate size of the
world so it's really about optimizing for the groups for collaboration.
So, let's talk a little bit of relational...sessions the session was
very introductory and in the sense that we showed you the surface hub in showed you how to
...apps but if you want to go deeper on inc you should take a look at the...sessions from the
direct in team the introductory one and advanced one they talk about multiple
...the same time we talk about in recognition they talk about
advanced processing and they would just show you how amazing this inc a
also from the small-screen to the big-screen this is a talk that goes and talks
about design based on screen size how do you do the adaptive design
and of course they're going to talk a little bit about design device families but you can take those
...form from large-screen...small-screen and apply here too.
So, thank you very much for coming and would like to open for...of course if you want to try
out the device we invited to come over to the showcase we invited
...download the sdk try it out play with the latest
bits and of course there's more information on surface hub dot com also...surface have dot
com so you can go and try it out and we're going to be available in the insider
...the showcase area for the whole afternoon you going to be able to find us but,
if you have questions please the mikes are open?
Could you please go to the mike I'm sorry because we have remote
...these and we need to make sure they can listen to?
Thank you very much for coming.
...hello, yeah,
I'm just wondering I've notice the seems natural...like you...
summing that you've drawn erroneously what kind of capabilities...
append have...terms of being able to...or...actions
...I'm glad you talk about it because actually the pen has an eraser and,
you can arrays...depend by default I didn't have to write encode for this so it
hasn't...a button on the back supernatural you...in the front erase the back lovett?
...have some existing applications for the ppi fifty-five and eighty is this hardware device
still support like having...pc plugged into...with usb connection for touch
input yes it does it has a...hookup secondary pc to it
and the imbedded pc and here have the ability to...have the normal...windows so
doesn't have kind of the discussions system this hardware is designed to run windows team
...okay, yeah, that you can plug replacement pc if you need to go beyond
the collaboration scenarios but it's really optimize for the
...appliance on the conference room you put in there and it's easy to
manage it's just going to be easy to keep it...
Thank you a is the...always
...it's ninety only when you touch you can get the pointer properties from
...to item...
So, if I want to make a pen...I touched it and I said okay this is my pen and I'm going to
changed pink and he's going to changes...blew it has to be touching no
let me explain how that works so when you touch when you do any
...events so drag move?
Touch releases actually even the touch over...can see...a mouse over
a little dot...shows up maybe we'll...the camera so they can see
...be able to see but there's a little dot that shows...when you over...that already gives you
pointer events everything every events touchy erasing everything will give you
...events...the...events who have that
...properties object and you can query the pointer id wireless id from any point-to-point
object so you can go and say if the...one taps the
read caller we associate...next time it goes down painted
red you can do that so that's what I did hear like I did that depend ideas associated with the color of
the inc so it becomes green...blue depending on the ten-ninety did you know-how many
...pointer id would be available concurrently so the you can simultaneously
...up to three paints simon things like all...this through the same time the
...these are unique so you can get a...as long as it on...more than three at
the same time you can get a different ideas for each of them and all of them will have unique ideas.
Any other questions please...can you I'm sorry
...please ask because remote that in these are going to...hear your question
to how do say the changes that we've just so we didn't show ced
savy and can collecting so on but...direct inc...about that
he talks about how to save and how to store also there's a cool sample on direct
aac available...get tub part of the
inc team samples so you should take a look at that it's all documented
their samples savy and collecting you can save with the
caller save with the metadata you can do all those things?
Any other questions once again if you are...shy or if you...just trial device
we're...be at the surface hub showcase right there in the middle area over there where there's
a windows demos will be over there like five-minute ourselves as we get up here are just
...up and go but we thank you very much for participation and it's been great to
present you guys thank you for...